

(a) +351 91 37 59 618

rafaelmdurante@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/rafaelmdurante

github.com/rafaelmdurante

www.rafaelmdurante.com

Lisbon, PT

Rafael Miranda Durante

Full-Stack Developer

Nationality S BR • IT

about

A software developer with an **AWS Solutions Architect** certificate, with passionate interest for technology, problem solving and knowledge sharing.

I feel comfortable when I am outside my comfort zone. Having an inquisitive mind, there is not a single day I do not learn something new - either to develop expertise or to broaden my knowledge.

As a former manager who worked very close to developers and customers, I have a deep sense of ownership for every work I do. If there is something that requires creativity and resilience, that is for me.

education

* in progress

Introduction to Computer Science

Harvard CS50x Online 2020

Full-Stack Java & JavaScript Developer

<Academia de Código_>

(A 14-Week Intensive && Immersive FullStack Programming Bootcamp)
2019

Web Development

Alura.com.br * / freeCodeCamp * / Udemy * 2018 - current

MBA in Business Management

Fundação Getúlio Vargas (FGV) - Brazil 2013 - 2014

Japanese Language and Culture

Nagasaki Wesleyan University - Japan 2008

Bachelor's degree in Languages

Universidade Paulista - Brazil 2004 - 2006

Certificates:

https://cursos.alura.com.br/user/rafaelmdurante https://www.freecodecamp.org/rafaelmdurante https://cs50.harvard.edu/certificates/ AWS Solutions Architect Associate

what i do on my spare time













experience

Set 2019 - Present

Full-Stack Developer

Deloitte Portugal

Experience on backend, frontend and infrastructure.

RESTful APIs with Ruby on Rails, MySQL and Angular. Tests with RSpec and Jasmine.

Development of Angular libraries, cli based on Ruby and Thor, AWS Serverless Application and plenty of shell scripts.

Established an effective workflow for the Angular libraries' development using git subtrees and shell scripting.

Infrastructure as code, using AWS CloudFormation and many other services.

Helped newcomers to become familiar with TypeScript and git workflow. Always caring for documentation and exchanging knowledge.

Mar 2012 - Jan 2019

Commercial Manager AGF Tatuhiby – Brazil

Responsible for driving and planning the company's commercial strategies. I implemented a new ERP, a sales pipeline and KPIs to understand the business from an analytical perspective. Always in touch with developers and customers.

Jan 2010 - Jan 2012

English Teacher

Cultura Inglesa Campinas - Brazil

technical skills

Daily Basis

Backend

Ruby on Rails • Sidekiq MySQL • Redis

Frontend

Angular • Material JavaScript • TypeScript HTML • CSS • Sass

Tools

Bash • Git • Docker BitBucket Pipelines Jira • Scrum Confluence

AWS

CloudFormation CloudWatch CloudTrail • Cognito • EC2 • ECR Elastic Beanstalk IAM • Lambda S3 • SAM • SES • SNS



Academic Knowledge

Java

Hibernate • Maven Spring MVC • Tomcat

Python

Flask • SQLite3

JavaScript

jQuery • MongoDB Node • WebPack Protractor

Complementary

UX Essentials

languages



C1 ENGLISH

B1

JAPANESE

B

B1

volunteer

Mentor Volunteer Migration Code, Lisbon, Portugal, 2020 Nagasaki Wesleyan University - Japan, 2008